# Raviteja Reddy SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Atlanta, GA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Raviteja-Reddy/98d9dce4d19eb3ea

Senior Software developer with 6 years thorough experience in delivering native Mobile solutions for iOS and Android, Mac OS X solutions, using Objective C, C++, Java, and Cross-platform Xamarin in C#. These mobile applications use several different application frameworks such as audio/video, Bluetooth, WiFi, animation, data communication, Accessibility, and support key features namely Push, SOAP & RESTful API interface, and data synchronization in background thread. Supportive and enthusiastic team players willing to take ownership of core development tasks and efficiently resolve technical issues.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Senior Mobile Developer

Softtrends LLC - Norcross, GA - August 2016 to Present

- Salesforce CRM Mobile Native iOS application for Synchronization and editing of data with Microsoft dynamics and Salesforce CRM. This application supports a customizable user interface, entity parsing and server communication module to support MS Dynamics and Salesforce, and can be customized for other CRM servers. This application can be configured to either mimic the entire functionality available on the CRM Web interface, or limit functionality based on logged in user. It works in both online and offline mode allowing the user to review downloaded data anytime and update date in disconnected mode, which gets synced to the server when the application is connected again.
- o Technologies: iOS, Objective C, C++, XML Web services, Salesforce CRM Services, In-App purchase, iCloud
- o Client: Softtrends LLC, Norcross, GA April 2017 to current
- o https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/mobile-crm-for-ms-dynamics-crm-online-free-version/id391475061?mt=8
- TREX Physical therapy Android tablet based application that interfaces with Servo connected to physical therapy units and controlled by a Bluetooth and USB connection. Application allows the therapist to set the exercise ranges for the patient as protocols and patients continue to do the exercise using those protocols. Visual indication of progress is shown to the user and user can control the movement in case the protocol results in pain. All session data and pain points are automatically captured and stores on backend server for analysis.
- o Technologies: Android native Java, Bluetooth, USB, RESTful API o Client: One Direct TREX, Atlanta, GA, Jan 2017 to March 2017
- Rojoli Field Force automation Xamarin iOS App that allows installers and field managers records their work on the field. Installers use this app to check-out and check-in installation work pushed down to their device from Store's Saleslogix server, and Field Managers use this App to capture details about their visit to the End Customer site for warranty, insurance coverage, and the Stores to conduct various EPA audits. Mobile Application supports dynamic form rendering as the various forms used by field managers are individually configured and pushed to the Mobile phone.
- o Technologies: Xamarin, iOS, Push technology, RESTful Service, Location Services o Client: Rojoli technologies LLC, Norcross, GA USA From August 2016 Dec 2016

## **Senior Mobile Developer**

Softtrends Software Private Limited - Bangalore, Karnataka - October 2011 to July 2016

- TripHoppr tripHoppr is a social travel application for iPhone that allows groups of people create trips, invite other Facebook friends to join and when they join, they have the ability to view trails followed by other trip members and the Albums of picture they have taken during the trip. It also allows members to publish trip trails with albums directly on Facebook for other friends to follow.
- o Technologies: iOS, Swift, Objective C, Push technology, RESTful Service, Location services, Google Map o Client: TripHoppr, Bangalore, India from Feb 2016 July 2016
- o https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/triphoppr/id1043550841?mt=8
- Microsoft Office 365 CRM Mobile Native iOS application that is based on the earlier Microsoft Dynamics CRM On-premise application developed in 2012. Went through a major redesign of the User Interface to support additional functionality provided by the Office 365 version, and the Server interface layer had to be modified to support the SOAP service provided by Office 365 CRM.
- o Technologies: iOS, Objective C, C++, SOAP, XML, iCloud, In-App purchase, Data sync using background thread o Client: Softtrends LLC, Norcross GA from July 2015 Jan 2016
- o https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/mobile-crm-for-ms-dynamics-crm-online-ipad/id410793296?mt=8
- LG Mobile+ Monitor Native iOS application that lets user control their Monitor using the iPhone with BLE Profile. With LG Mobile+ Monitor Software, users can change Volume, Input, Picture mode and other parameters of the Monitor from their iPhone.
- o Technologies: iOS, Swift, Objective C, Bluetooth, UIKit, CoreAnimation and CoreGraphics. o Client: LG Soft, Bangalore, India from March 2015 July 2015
- Dual Controller (Google cast) Objective C based Mac application that lets user control PC and Mobile using the shared keyboard and mouse attached to one computer using Google Cast based Dual Controller. Dual controller also allows user to control multiple Windows and Mac systems using a shared keyboard and mouse using Bluetooth.
- o Technologies: Cocoa, Objective C, CoreGraphics, AppKit, Accessibility, Socket communication (TCP/IP & UDP) o Client: LG Soft, Bangalore, India from Aug 2014 Feb 2015
- o http://www.lg.com/us/support-product/lg-25UM65-P#
- Screen Split Objective C application used to manage a single monitor to Split the Desktop with splitting layout such as 2 Screen (16:5), 2 Screen (1:1), 2 Screen (Horizontal balanced), 3 Screen (Left), 3 Screen (Right), 3 Screen (Top), 3 Screen (Bottom), 4 Screen (Balanced), 9 Screen (Balanced). Screen Split displays all connected LG monitor information.
- o Technologies: Cocoa, Objective C, AppKit, CoreGraphics, Accessibility. o Client: LG Soft, Bangalore, India from Apr 2014 July 2014
- o http://www.lg.com/us/support-product/lg-25UM65-P#
- TrueColor Pro Objective C application to assist users in calibrating an LG monitor. Calibration is very important aspect of the display devices to reproduce the accurate color information on the screen, which can be distorted due to aging or other various factors. True Color Pro ensures high color reproduction accuracy of Monitors using Hardware Calibration mechanism. TrueColor Pro calibrates monitor against the R/G/B Primaries, Brightness, Color Temperature and Gamma target values as set by user.
- o Technologies: Cocoa, Objective C, AppKit, CoreGraphics, ColorSync o Client: LG Soft, Bangalore, India from Nov 2013 Mar 2014
- o http://www.lg.com/us/support-product/lg-27EA83-D#
- Microsoft Dynamics CRM Mobile Native iOS application for Synchronization and editing of data with Microsoft dynamics and Salesforce CRM. This application supports a customizable user interface, entity parsing and server communication module to support MS Dynamics and Salesforce, and can be customized for other CRM servers. This application can be configured to either mimic the entire functionality available on the CRM Web interface, or limit functionality based on logged in user. It works in both online and offline mode allowing the user to review downloaded data anytime and update date in disconnected mode, which gets synced to the server when the application is connected again.

- o Technologies: iOS, Objective C, C++, UIKit, Audio/Video, web services, iCloud, In App Purchase o Client: Softtrends LLC, Norcross, GA from Aug 2012 October 2013
- o https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/mobile-crm-for-salesforce-crm-ipad/id605731736?mt=8
- Fast Input Native iOS application that allows user to easily select commonly used medical terms and inject them to the document being created with just a couple of touches. The medical terms are organized as words, phrases, paragraphs and information content. Import/Export module to Import new dictionaries into the UI or export edited dictionaries for backup and retrieval. The application communicates with the backend to detect any new dictionaries or books purchased by the user and download and use them.
- o Technologies: iOS, Objective C, C++, UIKit, Soap Services
- o Client: Sri Innovations, Charlotte NC from October 2011 July 2012

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor in Technology in Electronics & Communication Eng**

Sri Venkateshwara Institute of Science and Technology 2011

#### ADVANCED DIPLOMA IN EMBEDDED SYSTEMS in EMBEDDED SYSTEMS

ISM UNIVERSITY - Bangalore, Karnataka

#### **SKILLS**

Android (2 years), Bluetooth (2 years), iOS (6 years), Mac (6 years), Swift (2 years), Objective C (6 years), C# (2 years), Xamarin (2 years), Java (2 years), RESTful (4 years), Agile (4 years), Push Notification (4 years)

## LINKS

https://www.linkedin.com/in/prtsreddy

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

#### **SKILLS**

- Objective C 2011 current
- C++ 2011 current
- Android 2015 current
- Swift 2015 current
- iOS 2011 current
- Mac OS X 2013 current
- C# 2015 current
- Xamarin 2015 current
- UIKit 2011 current
- CoreAnimation 2011 current
- CoreGraphics 2011 current
- Core Services 2011 current
- AVFoundation 2011 current
- Background Tasks 2011 current
- Notification handling 2011 current
- Soap Services 2011 current

- RESTful API Calling 2011 current
- JSON/XML Parsing 2011 current
- Open GL S 2013 current
- BLE Bluetooth 2013 current
- TCP/IP 2013 current
- Audio/Video 2013 current
- QuartzCore2D 2014 2015
- SVN/GIT 2011 current
- HTML 2014 15
- JavaScript 2014 2015
- AppleScript 2015 current